ecological economics is an attempt to
integrate transcend disciplinary
boundaries in order to understand the
way humans interact with their
environment over several different
temporal and spacial scales and to be
able to address the the significant
problems that are facing the world today
no one discipline can really address
those kinds of problems which are at the
interface between human society and the
ecological life-support system so if we
really want to solve those problems we
have to take a much broader our system's
view over longer time periods and get
beyond the academic silos that have
compartmentalized knowledge in the past
ecosystems health and health as a way to
integrate this ability could you say
more about how you see I think in all of
this we have to focus on what the goals
are for the system in fact what we what
we would really like is to have a
healthy high quality of life for humans
and other species that we share the
planet with over an extended period of
time we want it to be sustainable so
this brings up the issues of how do we
conceptualize and how to require Phi the
health of a system of a complex system
and there I think new ways that we need
to start thinking about doing that
health is more than the absence of
disease health is well functioning well
functioning from the point of view of
the goals that I just mentioned includes
supporting human well-being and quality
of life and supporting the health of the
ecological life support system which
contributes significantly to to human
health and
being so in order to do that we have to
to think about all of the services that
ecological systems provide to to human
societies that support that that
well-being we have to think about the
health of the ecological system in terms
of its continued ability to to provide
those those services for that support
human health we have to think about
human health in a more preventive way as
as well functioning as high quality of
life rather than then simply the the
absence of the disease and that leads us
to be more preventive in our medicine
both for the human population but also
for the ecological system that supports
that human population so one way of
thinking about the system and the
support for human wellbeing is to
categorize things into four major types
of capital capital used very broadly in
this context I mean a stock that
supports a flow of services so we know
about the conventional forms of economic
capital what you might call the built
capital environment there's also human
capital which is individual people there
but much more than their labor it's more
it's also includes their their
intelligence their information their
creativity all the things that
individual humans provide us as well as
their individual health but then there's
also social capital which is the
interaction between people both formal
and informal networks and institutions
that allow human society to function as
a as a whole and finally there's natural
capital which is natural ecosystems and
all of the services that they that they
provide obviously these four types of
capital have different characteristics
and different ways that they can be
enhanced in different ways that they can
be eroded social capital required in
order to construct requires people to
interact in these networks and to build
trust in the networks it's so they can
they can depend on the society to to
help them achieve their goals natural
capital is is self replicating and self
repairing and so it's not that we can
build this natural capital but we can
certainly enhance and facilitate its its
self replication we can conserve it and
preserve it built capital obviously we
need to design that built capital
environment and we need to design it in
a way that's that enhances the other
forms of capital the the natural and the
social capital in particular as well as
the the human capital and we can
certainly invest in human capital in
various ways through through education
and etc so and research so we need to do
all of those things in a more integrated
way that acknowledges the joint
contributions of all four of these types
of capital to sustainable human
well-being the gund Institute for
ecological economics tries to carry out
this sort of research agenda we do that
by being a transdisciplinary research in
education unit we involve faculty and
students from all the different
components of the University and I think
the University of Vermont in general is
also trying to transcend these
disciplinary boundaries through various
mechanisms one mechanism has to do with
moving a larger fraction of the teaching
into problem-based and service learning
kinds of courses where we address real
problems in the
in the research environment in the
community at various scales from the
local to the regional to the global at
various places around the planet and by
doing that we can engage the
intelligence in the human capital of the
entire intellectual resources that we
have at the university on and engage
them in solving real problems that
society faces and that I think is one of
the major directions that both the gund
Institute and the University of Vermont
are are moving towards how do we
actually achieve this this integration
on the ground how do we transcend the
disciplinary boundaries and actually
create and design a more sustainable and
desirable future as a vehicle another
vehicle I think the proposed journal for
ecological design is a necessary
component to move us forward in this
direction we need to communicate what
what we're doing in all these fields and
also build bridges between all the
various disciplines and so having a
journal that really has that as its goal
to to build these bridges to integrate
all of the various components that are
going to be necessary to design a
sustainable future it's going to be more
than the built environment as I said
although that's a major component but
it's also going to involve designing the
economy designing the governance strict
system designing the institutions or
redesigning the institutions that that
we need in order to help us achieve this
this ambitious goal and I think this
journal will be an an important element
in that in that process